{
    "id": "80708ace3c7949bbab60479bd1f41c71",
    "title": "Intermediate Level Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "This material is inferior ............................... that.",
            "description": "After words like inferior and superior, we use 'to', not 'than'.",
            "answers": [
                "than",
                "with",
                "to"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Do you prefer ................................ of chocolate?",
            "description": "The words kind, class, sort, type etc. are all singular and should be used with this or that to modify a singular noun. The words kinds, sorts etc. are used with these and those to modify a plural noun",
            "answers": [
                "this sort",
                "these sorts",
                "these sort"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The garden shears .................................... used to clip the hedge.",
            "description": "Nouns like tongs, shears, tweezers, scissors etc. are always plural and should be used with plural verbs, unless of course the singular aspect is indicated by using ‘a pair of’",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Each of the students ....................................... asked to contribute their bit.",
            "description": "Each and every should be followed by a singular verb. ",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were",
                "has"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "A strimmer is a machine .................................... grass and weeds.",
            "description": "We use 'for + ing form' to denote the purpose of an object. ",
            "answers": [
                "to cut",
                "to cutting",
                "for cutting"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "To ..................................., he lost his job.",
            "description": "There are two words in no one. The possessive form of one is one's. ",
            "answers": [
                "noones surprise",
                "no ones surprise",
                "no one's surprise"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "You ........................................... working hard.",
            "description": "When there are two auxiliaries, the adverb usually goes after the first. ",
            "answers": [
                "have been definitely",
                "have definitely been",
                "definitely have been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "That kind of ....................................... not give me any amusement.",
            "description": "The words kind, class, sort, type etc. are all singular and should be used with this or that to modify a singular noun. The words kinds, sorts etc. are used with these and those to modify a plural noun.",
            "answers": [
                "joke does",
                "jokes does",
                "jokes do"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "There is a slight ......................................... between the two shades.",
            "description": "Difference is a noun different is an adjective. After an adjective (slight), we need a noun. ",
            "answers": [
                "difference",
                "different"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Few historians have written more .................................... than Gibbon.",
            "description": "Interesting is an adjective. Interestingly is an adverb. We need an adverb to modify the verb 'have written'.",
            "answers": [
                "interesting",
                "interestingly"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Our army ............................................. the enemy.",
            "description": "The position of the object at the end clearly indicates that this sentence is in the active voice. ",
            "answers": [
                "has defeated",
                "has been defeated",
                "was defeated"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Helen of Troy was more beautiful than ...................................",
            "description": "The expressions all women and any woman include Helen as well. So, if you used those options, the sentence would mean that Helen was more beautiful than she herself. ",
            "answers": [
                "all women",
                "any woman",
                "any other woman"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}